# Andrew Croshaw Junior Fullstack Software Developer

Kerry, Ireland

andrewcroshaw88@outlook.com

(+353) 0858126066 GitHub / LinkedIn / Portfolio

# **Executive Summary**

I am an enthusiastic and hardworking individual that is currently seeking an opportunity to change my career.

I have excellent communication, people and teamwork skills that I have built whilst working in the fast pace of the hospitality industry for the last 20 years, I can work well as part of a team, also on my own, using my initiative. I'm able to carry out instructions and ask if I am unsure. I pay attention to detail and work hard at getting it right.

I am always open to learning new skills and challenging myself to progress to new levels.

I take my responsibilities seriously. I am aware of health and safety issues in different working environments.

## **Education**

## December 2022 - 2023: Code Institute, Dublin, Ireland (Remote).

 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (E-Commerce), (Credit Rated by The University of the West of Scotland)

HTML/CSS Essentials	Merit	Full-Stack Toolkit	Pass
JavaScript Essentials	Merit	E-commerce Applications	Pass
Python Essentials	Merit		

## September 2005 –2007: East Devon College, Devon, England.

BTEC National Diploma: IT Practitioners (Software Development), Qualification: (Pass, Pass, Pass)

Language & Communications	Pass	System Analysis and Design	Pass
Computer Systems	Pass	Software Development Project	Pass
Introduction to Software Development	Pass	Programming Concepts and Practice	Pass
Communications Technology	Merit	Website Management	Pass
Visual Programming	Pass	Human Computer Interface	Pass
Application Software Development	Pass	E-Commerce	Pass
Computational Methods	Pass	System Justification	Pass
Website Development	Pass	Software Applications	Merit
Business Information Systems	Pass	Expert Systems	Unclassified

• Adult Literature Certificate level 2,

# September 2003 – 2005: Cullompton Community College, Devon, England.

#### GCSE's:

Religious Studies (Philosophy & Ethics)	В	D&T: Resistant Materials Technology	С
Mathematics	С	English	D
Information and Communication Technology	D	English Literature	D
Science Double Award	DD	German	F
Art & Design	В		

#### Certificates/Courses

## **Udemy Courses:**

- Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS (37.5 hours)
- The Complete JavaScript Course 2024 From Zero to Expert! (68.5 hours)
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp (42 hours)
- Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations, and More! (28 hours)
- Build a Quiz App with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (2 hours)
- Wed Design for Wb Developers: Build Beautiful Websites! (2.5 hours)

# **Technical Skillset**

Technologies:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, Node.js

Databases:

MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks:

Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

Version Control:

Git, GitHub

#### **Portfolio Projects**

Cosbranok - https://github.com/A-Croshaw/cosbranok

This is a featured website to represent the Cosbranok Re-enactment Society. Technologies used: HTML and CSS

• **Hi-Low-Game** - https://github.com/A-Croshaw/hi-low-game

This is an online representation of the hi low game. Technologies used: HTML, CSS & JavaScript.

• Riddles - https://github.com/A-Croshaw/Riddles

Riddles is a multiple choice riddles game. Using low level Python that displays in the console and linked to google sheets where the riddles and answers stored for use within the game. Technologies used: Python, Gspread.

• Menu Manager - https://github.com/A-Croshaw/Menu\_Manager

Menu Manager is a site that allows the user to create recipes, dishes and menus. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 5.3.2, JavaScript, Python/ Django, Elephant SQL, Cloudinary.

Rubvs - https://github.com/A-Croshaw/Rubvs-23

Rubys is E-Commerce book store where users can search and buy books with full functional check using stripe. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, **Bootstrap 5.2.3**, JavaScript, Python/Django, Elephant SQL, Cloudinary.

Andrew-Patricia - <a href="https://github.com/A-Croshaw/Andrew-Patricia">https://github.com/A-Croshaw/Andrew-Patricia</a>

Andrew-Patricia is a website created for a wedding that allows people to check information and rsvp through. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

#### **Work Experience**

March 2024 - Present, Heathers, Grounds Man/ Gardener, Killarney, Ireland.

This is a full-time job. Working: Weekdays.

- . Keeping the grounds tidy and presentable
- Growing produce for the café and for supplying to other establishments.
- Working to strict health and safety measures

June 2023 – March 2024, The Ballyroe Hights Hotel, Chef De Partie, Tralee, Ireland. This was a full-time job. Working: days, evenings and weekends.

- Food preparation
- Cooking and serving food to a high quality
- Providing food with dietary requirements
- · Checking and ordering stock and ensuring
- . Keeping the kitchen in a tidy and safe working environment.
- Working to strict food hygiene conducts and practices.

April 2018 – May 2023, The Dromhall Hotel, Chef De Partie, Killarney, Ireland. This was a full-time job. Working: days, evenings and weekends.

- Food preparation
- Cooking and serving food to a high quality
- Providing food with dietary requirements
- Checking and ordering stock and ensuring
- . Keeping the kitchen in a tidy and safe working environment.
- Working to strict food hygiene conducts and practices.

July 2015 - June 2016, The Roast House, Chef De Partie, Tralee, Ireland.

This was a full-time job. Working: days, evenings and weekends.

- Food preparation
- Cooking and serving food to a high quality
- Providing food with dietary requirements
- Checking and ordering stock and ensuring
- Keeping the kitchen in a tidy and safe working environment.
- Working to strict food hygiene conducts and practices.

#### Additional Information/Interests

- I am currently working on building up the Menu Manager site to include costings from the products up to
  the final menus that will automatically change when the cost of produce goes up or down to give the true
  70% GDP. Also moving it from a browser to a desktop application for better user experience.
- Regular engagement on Slack tech forum.
- Fluent English

References available on request.